well the first thing was you mentioned
being honest with yourself I do think
that one of the great things about
psychedelics is they kind of force you
to be honest with yourself right it's
often being said that they sort of
mirror to who you are right now so there
is that aspect I think is really
important idea of self confrontation I
think that's also one of the reasons
people can be a bit trepidatious or
anxious also because it's not
necessarily a clear mirror right the
message you might get back is one not
you should take with great importance
but it's often not going to be a message
where it's like oh yeah I got that I can
just translate that into my life
immediately it's all very very clear and
the experience of course is taking place
largely imagistic alee and like I
suppose growth and development in life
being honest with yourself is something
that takes time and so the feedback you
get is something that you have to work
with yeah so they're coming to a point
of responsibility as well going back to
that journal article the importance of
context in psychedelic experience there
was a call out by the researcher Robyn
card Harris for the cyclic community
because we are at this point where that
Boulder is science roll down the hill we
are at this turning point there is a
there is a there is still a risk that
something could go very wrong in a trial
and these medicines could be delayed or
there is a risk that people become
increasingly concerned about deaths at
Rainbow Serpent which are very rarely if
ever ever caused by a psychedelic any
implicated in a combination of many
drugs but the safety profile
psychedelics is incomparable to really
any other substance so safety profiles
is one core differentiating feature and
there's good information on this I can't
point you in the direction of that right
now I know David not David not David not
he'll be here in Melbourne next week did
the famous comparison of the harm of
drugs study for the British government
which he was acting
as the advisor for drugs to the British
government that point and after which
she was fired for basically telling the
truth which was psilocybin and deem a
fairly harmless and drugs that we
control that society at least consumes
very regularly like alcohol and tobacco
were right on the other end of the scale
at the most dangerous in the same
ballpark is heroin and crack cocaine so
that's that's something we can be aware
of that psychedelics are safe for the
body but as you say responsibility and
the mind and setting so back to that
Journal article there was a call at me
Robin Carhartt Harris
for cyclic community for those of us who
are already already experienced or who
will experience or who are going to take
psychedelics I've often thought about
the responsibilities of the rule breaker
I first discovered it at a passion er
well I'll probably not true by first
became truly aware of it of a passionate
retreat where I really wanted to write
at the past ran I'm not sure if you're
aware it's a very very straight you have
to wake up and go to sleep at certain
times eat at certain times no talking at
all no form of communication you look
down at the ground because well ten days
of silence and I gaze Camille can
ricochet in the mind if you've been
quiet for well six seven days and it
would no interaction so there's you very
have to be very careful with how you
affect others and I really wanted to
write you will not do not meant to write
I really wanted I was having some really
profound thoughts I thought I might lose
them
and so I thought okay well maybe at
night time I'll write in my book on
covers but actually there's a scratching
noise of the pen might might be heard by
the girl in the bed over the curtain and
maybe that will confuse her maybe or
maybe I want to write on the person's
breaking the rules was that mean for me
so I ended up writing in the shower a
partner
I tell this story because it made me
realize the responsibility of the rule
breaker and that is if you break rules
you better break them like they didn't
need to be there in the first place